Adam Novitch

Website: https://adamnovitch.github.io/ Contact: adam.novitch@gmail.com 914-246-8715

Skills: Application Development, Embedded Development, Linux, Scripting, Source Control, CI/CD, Unit Test

Programming Languages: Ada, C/C++, Bash (Linux Shell), Python, JavaScript, Ruby

Tools: Git, GitLab, VectorCAST, GDB, JenkinsCI, Simulink

Software Engineer

Embedded and Application Software Engineer with 9 years of professional experience in developing for commercial avionics, marine defense, and passenger elevator systems and products. Experience encompasses entire software development lifecycle including requirements definition, design documentation, software design and development, unit test, system integration, continuous integration, and mentorship. Projects have often required cross-disciplinary work as well as continued communication with clients or end users.

Work Experience

OTIS Elevator Company, Farmington, CT, November 2021 - Present

Motion Controller Software - Smart Service Integration

Implemented streamlined field tests based on existing procedures to reduce per-car installation time by 5 hours. Integrated controller software and cloud database to work with mobile application.

Updated controller software to run on updated platform.

Tested code and procedures on simulation equipment.

Position Simulation Software

Maintained test software by updating Simulink models.

General Dynamics Electric Boat Corporation, New London, CT, November 2016 - October 2021

HMCCS & Columbia-class Submarine Ship Control

Participated in full SDLC of ship control software for \$12B ballistic missile submarine.

Developed code in Ada and C, and performed unit tests using a mix of Ada and C drivers and VectorCAST.

Provided mentorship to junior engineers.

Updated C code to run application on partially POSIX compliant RTOS system, using inter

Supported source control framework, build scripts, CI/CD.

Created API/library used by multiple applications.

Created and maintained source control usage guidelines.

Software Engineering Development Environments (SwEDE) Board member.

Operational Excellence (OPEX) Award Recipient, 2020 - GitLab Process Guideline Document

ENSCO Avionics, Endicott, NY, *January 2014 – November 2016*

Boeing 777 Cabin Control Panel

Configured custom open source embedded Yocto Linux.

Integrated applications with operating system using system services.

Deployed nightly builds of OS images for virtual machine and target hardware.

Supported Git/GitLab source control, build scripts and continuous integration.

Tested touchscreen control panel system using Ruby.

Engine Control Unit Test

Tested for defense and commercial engine control software in a Unix environment.

Education

Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute (RPI), Troy, NY

B.S. Computer & Systems Engineering, May 2013